Yaovi Ametepe

Blockchain & Web Developer, Smart Contracts creator auditor.

PHP, Laravel, NodeJS, React, Solidity

INFOS & CONTACT

Male, 29

(228) 92127235 | 99119494

yaoviscoder@gmail.com

yaovicoder.github.io

github.com/yaovicoder

Lome

SOCIAL

in linkedin.com/in/yaoviametepe

@yaoviametepe

KEY ACHIEVEMENT

During 2014-2016 period, I cofounded eFortis Inc. with two mates. It was a startup which aimed to deliver cute-edged web development and IT consultancy services to companies that lack suitable IT managment processes and tools. Even though the startup failed two years later, mainly due to lack of investment funds targetted to \$1.5 million, this was one of the richest experiences I had inmy professional life.

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a competent, experimented and highly motivated blockchain and web developer with a pleasant personality and very good organizational skills. I love team working, leading people, learning, and growing my skillset with greatest technologies.

During my quest of challenges I discovered **Blockchain** three years ago and failed literally in love with this great and disruptive technology. Since then I worked with some great Blockchain projects.

I am actually building **BloqPay**, a wallet that will allow users of famous social apps to interact with blockchain and send/receive **Ethereum** based tokens.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Developer

BitcoinZeroX (bitcoinzerox.net)

Since Aug 2018

BitcoinZeroX is a new cryptocurrency coin created from a triple fork and very focused on privacy and anonymous transactions. The project is conducted by a german team. As Developer on BitcoinZeroX project, my responsibilities include:

- Complete redesign of website.
- Creation of Payment gateway & API for easy integration on partners and vendors websites
- Building community project voting-funding platform
- Creation of web and mobile wallet
- Creation of social wallet

Smart Contract Builder/Auditor

Contractium, SHOPCoin

Since November 2017

I was responsible of Creating and Auditing Ethereum based Smart
Contracts for various cryptocurrency project.

My responsibilities included:

- Creation of smarts contracts using Solidity Programming language to handle ICOs.
- Auditing Smarts Contracts written by other devs in team to make sure they respect security compliance.

Web Architect & Project Manager

EVAME GROUP

Since 2016

I was responsible of the design and deployment of human resources, production and payroll software.

- Project management,
- Analysis of customer needs,
- Drafting of the project specifications and project plan,
- Creation of the project team,
- Proposal and adoption of software architecture,
- Coding of some main functionalities,
- Periodic reporting to the client,
- Training different users

SKILLS

- 2 years of Blockchain development creating Ethereum smart contracts using Solidity
- 7 years of professional development using framework Zend, Laravel,
 Symphony
- CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS mastered
- Experience using Bootstrap and LESS and/or Sass
- Experience working with React
- Experience working with distributed version control systems (Git, Bucket)
- SOLID and DRY development
- Experience with maintaining continuous deployment workflows for PHP applications (Vagrant, Jenkins)
- Consistent, Clean, Concise, and well documented code writing
- Understanding of common web application security attacks and how to prevent them (SQL injection, XSS, CSRF)
- Ability to work using existing code and upgrading it

PROJECT MANAGEMENT (SBOK)

- Planning
- Resources management
- Risk management
- Conflict management
- Time management
- Quality control management
- Customer Relationship Management

SYSTEM ADMINISTATION

- Linux systems administration (LPIC I Level)
- Understands common Linux system tools' configuration (system, firewall)

COMMUNICATION

- French native
- Good knowledge of English, speaking & writing

OTHER

- Exceptional communication, presentation, and organization skills
- Self-reliant learner and creative problem-solver
- Teamwork, can work as Team Leader as Team player
- Particular interest for OpenSource
- International mobility (can relocate)

WORK EXPERIENCE (continued)

CTO & CO-Founder

EFORTIS INC

Jan 2014 - Jun 2016

During this period I wore many hats. EFORTIS INC was a startup and being CTO there meant being Coder, **Web Solutions**Architect, Team Manager.

AS SOLUTION ARCHITECT/ENGINEER

- Work with other team members to specify, update, and prioritize software system requirements according to specifications
- Follow sound engineering principles to find practical solutions to meet specifications
- Provide scripts and documentation for maintaining secure and upto-date PHP Code
- Provide great code in PHP using standardized development frameworks (Zend most of time), procedures and processes
- Write Technical proposal for tenders' submission

> AS TEAM MANAGER

I was mainly responsible of managing team of developers (local and international teams) on various web projects mainly built using various frameworks including Zend, Symphony, .NET

- Write Projects Specifications
- Manage developers' units
- Control and monitor projects, insuring teams meet deadlines
- Report to customers and CEO
- Provide training to developers
- Ensure developers understand and respect our standards

Team leader of Web Development office

IPNET EXPERTS S.A

Sept 2012 - Dec 2013

My responsibility was to plan teams' activities and ensures deliveries meet

- I built websites and web applications
- I managed team of developers (local and remote) to ensure deliveries meet deadlines
- I used to do some extra Unix Systems Administration tasks like maintain company's and customers' Linux based System (Debian, RHEL5,6)

CURRENT PERSONNAL PROJECTS

BloqPay

A Decentralized app couplet with a socialbot working like a crypto wallet that runs on top of social messaging apps (Facebook, Twitter, Discord, Telegram...) allowing users to send funds directly in chats.

Charity-Tree

A web platform that will increase transparency of donations to charity organizations since prime donors to final recipients.

Auhor.me

Auto publishing web platform that will allow authors to auto publish and sell their eBooks very quickly and simply. The platform will use cryptocurrency as main payment method what will lead to avoiding huge taxes of book publishing firms.

REFERENCES

Upon Request

EDUCATION

Technology, Software Programming
CUWA, Science and Technology School, Lome
High School degree in Sciences
Kouvahey High School, Lome

Bachelor of Sciences – Information

2011

2007

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

- 2017) Blockchain Algorithms, Cryptocurrencies transactions and security
- 2016) Scrum Fundamentals Certificate SFC®, <u>Certificate number</u>:
 103441
- 2015) Human Resources Management Training
- 2014) Scrum Methodology Training (Agile Project Management)
- 2013) Project Management Fundamentals PMF® Training

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Scrabble
- Crosswords
- Bitcoin and Crypto trading
- Jogging
- Football (Soccer)
- Cycling
- Nature's beauty